Hi guys, welcome back to the channel and
today I'm going to show you how you can
deploy a Django application on railway
for 100% free. So railway is basically a
deploying service and host hosting
service as well which deploys your
applications in just in very simple
steps including automation for GitHub
repositories as well. So we're just
going to learn that how we can deploy a
Django application from our GitHub
repository in just few simple clicks. So
let's begin. So first of all head up to
the railways official website
railway.com and create an account
railway using GitHub Google account or
email as you wish and we can create the
account by clicking on this login button
and you can create something with GitHub
or you can also create it with Google
and just normal email. All right. So
after you have created your railway
account you can head up to the dashboard
which would which would look like
something like this. So we can create a
new project here. And let me just show
you what are we going to deploy today.
This is the test Django application
inside my GitHub repository which is um
just a simple uh structure having an
application app and we have the test
which is the back end of this
application and we have a manage.py and
then we have a requirements.txt which I
have built using the pip freeze command.
All right. So we can now move forward to
deploying our railway application. So
for this just click on create a new
project and you have some options right
here. So we are just going to deploy it
from a GitHub
repository. So if you are you have not
logged in with GitHub account inside
your railway application then you will
not be able to see these two
repositories like I am going to see. So
for this you will have to configure the
GitHub app by clicking on this button
and then it will prompt you to uh pass
in the username and password for your
GitHub account and then you'll be logged
in with your GitHub account inside your
Railway application. All right. So for
me I have logged in inside Railway using
my GitHub account. So I have I am able
to see my two repositories right here.
So for this uh demonstration we are
going to deploy the test Django
application. So I'll just click on this
and now it will start the deployment
process. So currently it does not have
any start or build command. So it is
going to pop some error for us something
like uh we do not have a start command.
So for this we are going to change the
start command and the build command for
this. So let me just wait for this and
let's wait for this to throw some error
for us.
So as you can see in the settings we
have uh no start command and no build
command. So we have to edit these
commands as uh for now. So let's just
wait for seeing what's happening right
here.
So for this project we I think railway
has automatically automatically
detected. So for cut so for this project
I think railway has automatically
detected that it's a Django project and
it has done the basic build and start
commands on its own. But if it gives uh
some kind of error for you can define uh
start commands on your own like I'm
going to do now. So you have you can
click a build command here which can be
your build command something like tape
install requirements.txt txt and you if
you have some static folder you can also
run uh collect static function by
writing double emp% and then you can
write python manage py
uh collect static and make sure you you
write no input because we do not have
access
to the CLI for this server right now and
also if you want to run the migrations
you can also run it right here by
running the command pythm py I make
migrations after the double amperson.
All right. So for me, I do not have any
static files or migrations. So I'll just
skip this part and I'll just use the pip
install our requirements.txt. And then
for the start command, we can just put
something like python manage.py ey run
server and make sure to run this
application on the
0.0.0.08,000 port, not the 127 uh port
because
0.0.0.0 zero actually enables all the
hosts to to access our Django
application. All right. So we can set
this as the custom start command and
this as the custom build command and
this will also deploy our application.
So now if I save these uh commands and
apply the changes, it should start the
deployment process again and we'll see
uh how it goes. So it has started the
process and you can see it is starting
to install the requirements using the
command pip install- r requirements.txt.
txt. Perfect. And now I think it will
attempt to start the application using
the command uh python
manage.py.ver. So let's just wait for
this application to go
live. All right. So you can see my
service is actually active right now.
That means my application is running but
we cannot access it on a public IP right
now because we have not generated a
public IP. So for this just go to the
settings of the project and now uh you
can go inside the I think you can go
All
right. So to make this cut, all right.
So to make this uh project go live on a
public URL, you can head to the settings
in the project and then go to the
visibility setting and then click on
change visibility and paste the project
name here. So this now we can actually
uh make this now we have actually made
this project public. So I think we will
be able to access our project with the
URL of our project. So let's just see
how we are able to access it. I just
click here and then we can see the
public URL right
here. All right. So I I'll now show you
how you can make your application go
public with a public URL. So just click
on this project right here and then go
inside the settings and scroll down till
you see public networking. So now we
need to create a domain for this. So now
click on generate domain right here. And
now it will generate a domain for us
which will help uh us to access this
application on our browser. So we it has
generated this port uh this URL right
here. And now if I open this URL, I
should be able to access a Django
application in any browser. So let's
just test it out.
And perfect. So we have got the sample
page here which is this is a sample
Django project which is which was
exactly present inside my GitHub
repository. So we have successfully
deployed our Django application on
railway for 100% free. So we basically
we get a $5 worth of free credits which
is a lot when it comes to building hobby
projects or static websites. So we uh
have this is essentially free for a long
time a period. So we have learned how we
can deploy a Django application on
railway and that's it for the video. So
thanks for watching.