in this video let us see how to deploy
ajango project on playway so this is the
Jango project as you can see it is
running on the local Force let us see
how to deploy this project to the raway
it is similar to ver.com so let us see
how to deploy to this before we proceed
ahead we need to create some
configuration files so that raway can
deploy our project easily so this is my
jro project this is where my settings
that Bei is located and this is my jro
app we need to create the prop file the
file don't have any extension so this is
the file make sure you don't type any
extension then inside this we need to
copy and paste this I will provide the
link of this repository in the
description you can Che that out so let
me copy this and paste it in the prop
file here in the project name replace it
with your project name in this case
portfolio is me project name I will typ
that here
and also change that to portfolio now we
have created this stop file next we need
to create the run. text file here we
need to define the python version to get
the python version that is running on
your system open the terminal or command
front I'm going to open your terminal
here just type python iPhone iPhone
version this will give you the version
of python let me copy this python
version and paste it here
next we need to create the requirement.
x file mandator you need to have the Gan
and the white noise so let me type the
requirements here the gicon and the
white noise are mandatory here because
using the white no we will save the
static
files so let's save this file also now
we have created these three files then
we need to change the settings we need
to add this white noes in the
settings.py file let me copy that and
open your settings.py
file here replace allow Force to Aster
because we don't know the URL on the
raway app so that's why we allow it to
Aster here in the middleware just P it
here through the White Noise We Will St
the static files because rway itself
don't serve the static files we will
save it through the white nice then at
the bottom of the file we need to add
another line so let me copy the second
line and paste it at the bottom of the.
pyi now we have completed the settings
that
file I think we have configured
everything let push it to the G up
now let me add this and then commit this
files so let's push the changes to the
GitHub now I have successfully updated
all my files to the GitHub
after you proceed I make sure you upload
all your project files to the GitHub so
this is my GitHub now I have uploaded
all my project files here after you
upload all your project files to the gab
then just go to the railway. app this is
the
website click on start a new project and
select the deploy from GitHub repo click
that and click on configure GitHub
app here we need to authenticate our
GitHub here just scroll down and select
the repos stories so this is my repos
story let me select that and click our
save so now select the portfolio and
click on deploy
now when you go to the dashboard now you
can see a new project has been built
here click on that as you can see our
project has been
built select the lest build now and
select the build
locks as you can see here you considered
our project has been deploying just give
you a few
minutes if you done everything correct
then we don't have to do anything here
the rway will do everything for us and
deploy
it as you can see now our project has
been deployed
successfully this is our URL let me
click the
URL when you register for in the railway
for the first time you won't get the URL
straight away what is just go to the
settings and under the public networking
you will have to generate your to
URL so remember to do this otherwise the
website link will not be usable for you
so let me open that URL as you can see
our Jango app has been deployed
successfully but when you go to the
admin panel when you try to log to the
admin panel
we will get a error like CSR
verification file for this we need to
change something in the settings. we may
file so let me copy this
line I paste it in the top of the
settings that VII and P paste it here
here we need to provide the URL of the
Jango
project so this is our project
URL we can find it also in the elant
dashboard copy the URL without the admin
URL let's copy all of that make sure you
include the htvs and paste it
here so we will have to redeploy it for
the just push it to the G now let me
open a new tab
and I will perform the get add
command and also commit
it let's push to the get up now let me
go to the LI
dashboard when you refresh the page you
can see a new build has been created
click on that and select the build
logs you can see that our deployment has
been restarted just give you a few
minutes now our deployment has been
successful let me go to the
URL let's misstion the admin panel now
let me log in using my current sh
as you can see now we successfully log
to the AC
dashboard if you want to add a custom
domain to this just go to the settings
and if you scroll down you can see
something like public here under the
public networking you can see option of
adding a custom domain here if you have
a domain just type
that and select the port choose the port
suggested by the raway and click on ADD
domain so after you add this record to
the domain provider then the domain will
be successfully configured to this val.
app so this is how you deploy janga app
to the r. app